<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on Le Baron de Charlus</title><link>https://lebaron.sh/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on Le Baron de Charlus</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Le Baron de Charlus</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 13:52:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lebaron.sh/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dockerize Nova client</title><link>https://lebaron.sh/p/dockerize-nova-client/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 13:52:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lebaron.sh/p/dockerize-nova-client/</guid><description>&lt;p>With OVH Public Cloud, it is possible for you to control your OpenStack instances directly from the Nova client.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is rather practical to go through the command line rather than having to access the manager which is often, let us say it, slow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But to avoid having to prepare each time a working environment compatible with Nova, I find more interesting to directly create a Docker image for this purpose.
In this way, no more need to install anything except the Docker daemon on its workstation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setup Rancher cluster on OVH Public Cloud</title><link>https://lebaron.sh/p/setup-rancher-cluster-on-ovh-public-cloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 19:04:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lebaron.sh/p/setup-rancher-cluster-on-ovh-public-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://lebaron.sh/Images/rancher_logo.jpeg" alt="Rancher logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world of hosting is changing, and so is the world of application development. Today we are turning less and less to dedicated hosting for a single application, but more to build the infrastructure that will support it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this sense, we prefer to use an Iaas solution on dedicated &amp;ldquo;bare metal&amp;rdquo; for our application overlay than pure &amp;ldquo;bare metal&amp;rdquo; per service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Application deployment missions pushed by developers must fit with the technology and logic of production. Which &lt;code>pipelines&lt;/code> should we use for our &lt;code>CI&lt;/code>, &lt;code>CD&lt;/code> ?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>