<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Kaderovski</title>
    <link>https://kaderovski.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Kaderovski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Kaderovski</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 08:12:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kaderovski.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Python development environment configuration</title>
      <link>https://kaderovski.com/posts/ultimate-python-development-environment-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 08:12:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaderovski.com/posts/ultimate-python-development-environment-configuration/</guid>
      <description>The Old Way Direnv  What is direnv and how it works direnv installation Shell configuration How Python works with direnv   Pyenv  Installation and Configuration Use pyenv with direnv   Poetry  What is Poetry Poetry installation Shell configuration New project Existing project Poetry usage Link Poetry with direnv   GPG  Generate a key Get key ID   Pass  Pass installation Pass usage   Tomb  Tomb installation Tomb usage   Secrets with Direnv and Pass Direnv advanced configurations  Check for commands dependencies Third-party binaries Third-party configs   Final template Conclusion  Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not saying virtualenv methods are bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Web Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://kaderovski.com/posts/little-web-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 08:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaderovski.com/posts/little-web-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes making small OneJob services is efficient in terms of time, organization, functionality. In the example of this article, I will try to show how it can be relevant to write `microscripts&#39; under this model.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say we want to make sure, for a given list of sites, that they all return 200 codes in less than 2s, in which case we&amp;rsquo;ll get a notification on Slack. The sources for these posts are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Watcher Manager Python3</title>
      <link>https://kaderovski.com/posts/event-watcher-manager-python3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 12:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kaderovski.com/posts/event-watcher-manager-python3/</guid>
      <description>On one specific request, I had to work on the elaboration of an automating program reacting on SFTP users updates.
The main technical issue of this request is that the SFTP protocol does not have a logging system.
I had heard about the pyinotify library so I started working on it.
The project is presented in its primary mechanism, for more details, I invite you to read the sources.
Technical requests concerning the project Details of the context of realization : Details of the context of realization :.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
